<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on KC9WWH</title><link>https://kc9wwh.net/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on KC9WWH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kc9wwh.net/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://kc9wwh.net/archives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kc9wwh.net/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://kc9wwh.net/about-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kc9wwh.net/about-me/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a seasoned Customer Success Manager with over 8 years of experience in enterprise solutions and SaaS, I am driven by a passion for helping clients achieve exceptional outcomes. My journey in the tech industry has been anything but conventional, and that’s what makes it so exciting. With a career spanning diverse roles and industries, I’ve cultivated a unique perspective that allows me to bridge the gap between technology and human connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Jamf, I had the privilege of leading a talented team responsible for managing a $50M book of business. Through strategic planning and a relentless focus on customer-centric initiatives, we achieved a 20% customer growth rate, a remarkable 97% retention rate, and increased revenue by 25% through advanced adoption strategies. More recently, at Files.com, I focused on simplifying complex solutions to drive efficiency for clients, enhancing their workflows by an impressive 300% through process automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into Customer Success, I honed my technical expertise in a variety of roles. As a Systems Administrator at Lands&amp;rsquo; End, I tackled enterprise-level IT challenges. At U.S. Cellular, I served as a Network Field Engineer, ensuring reliable connectivity across a wide range of environments. My tech journey began even earlier when I worked as a Network Technician for the Black River Falls School District—a role I took on while still in high school, laying the foundation for my career in technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But my story doesn’t end there. Outside the professional realm, I’ve always been drawn to community service and hands-on problem-solving. As a licensed Ham Radio operator, I’ve combined my technical skills with my love for communication, contributing to emergency preparedness initiatives. My time as a volunteer Firefighter, EMT, Hazmat Technician, and Rescue Technician taught me the value of teamwork, quick decision-making, and staying calm under pressure—skills that continue to influence my approach to leadership and customer success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through every chapter of my career and life, one thing has remained constant: my enthusiasm for learning, connecting, and making a meaningful impact. Whether it’s optimizing SaaS adoption strategies, mentoring teams, or diving into the latest tech trends, I’m passionate about building solutions that empower people and businesses to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for stopping by—I’m thrilled to have you here. Let’s connect, collaborate, and share ideas to drive success together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://kc9wwh.net/about-me/cover.jpg"
width="6016"
height="4016"
srcset="https://kc9wwh.net/about-me/cover_hu_8f3f45ad7d62955a.jpg 480w, https://kc9wwh.net/about-me/cover_hu_24ff6022095c3f81.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Passion Led Us Here"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="149"
data-flex-basis="359px"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a class="link" href="https://unsplash.com/@goian?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=unsplash" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Ian Schneider&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a class="link" href="https://unsplash.com/photos/two-person-standing-on-gray-tile-paving-TamMbr4okv4?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=unsplash" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://kc9wwh.net/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kc9wwh.net/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>